RAJAT MAHESHWARI

MANAGER- SALES & MARKETING

Address Delhi, R-10 First Floor Model Town-3 Delhi-110009

Phone 9711573252

E-mail rajat.gpglobal@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Experienced Sales & Marketing Manager with over 8 years of experience in oil and gas industry. Seeking a responsible position in an organization where I can contribute my knowledge & skills towards the accomplishment of organizational goals.

Work History

2020-08 - BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

Current

HEIL, Gurgaon, Haryana

- Build a strong and sustainable interface with the management team of HERO and TVS for increasing business share and to identify new projects / opportunities.
- Build, coordinate and deliver the pipeline of initiatives and projects related to automotive market.
- Generate leads and manage opportunities with new customers and applications until business is secured.
- Identify and evaluate market opportunities to be able to enter new and growing applications, identify and support the launch of new products.
- Work with the sales team to develop and maintain prospective customers and grow turnover in new products.
- Coordinate with the existing plant for the target achievement on day to day basis.

2019-06 - 2020-07

DEPUTY MANAGER

GP GLOBAL, Gurgaon, Haryana

- Evaluated suppliers to assess quality, timeliness and compliance of deliveries, maintain tight cost controls and maximize business operational efficiency.
- New product Launch, Marketing and Branding- Digital marketing.
- Responsible for introducing a seed business in Haryana and Uttar Pradesh. Established a market of 5Cr.
- Enhanced supervisory and leadership abilities by working closely with mentoring.
- Leading a biomass business in North India with a team of 8 person.
- Dealing with distributors, traders and B2B segment.

2014-11 - 2019-05

Area sales Manager

Thermax India Ltd

- B2B Sales, Channel sales.
- Industrial Sales for industrial products like Boilers, Biomass fuel boilers.
- Dealing in Thermax Boiler and stoves with proper heating solution.
- Handling a Haryana region which includes Manesar, Bhiwadi, Chaupanki, Sonepat, Kundli, Gurugram, Faridabad Etc.
- Handling a team of 5 person which include salesperson and service engineer.
- Responsible for all the marketing activities like participating in Aahar and other exhibitions, presentations to customers.

2012-07 - 2014-10

Area Sales Executive

Aktion Safety Solution Pvt Ltd

- Working as Area Sales Executive and responsible for marketing and Business Development, meeting with customers and follow actions.
- Deals with Manufacturing Companies, Construction Sites & Automobile Company.
- Handle B2B & Channel Sales.
- Having a team of two person under me and handling an area of Noida,
 Greater Noida, Ghaziabad, and Faridabad to Agra.
- My major client are: LNT (Infra and B&F), shapoorji, Tata Projects, ABB, Graziano, Skyline, Indraprastha Gas Ltd, Adani, Honeywell, supertech, Havells, Ace Group, Amrapali, Whirlpool.

Education

2008-07 - 2012-07

B. Tech: Mechanical

Jind Institute Of Engineering & Technology, Kurukshetra University - KURUKSHETRA

2007-04 - 2008-03

Bachelor of Science: NON-MEDICAL

KGSBV - DELHI

2005-04 - 2006-03

High School Diploma

D.A.V. PUBLIC SCHOOL - FARIDABAD

Accomplishments

- Title: NTPC SUMMER TRAINING
- Location: Badarpur, New Delhi
- Duration: 4 weeks (July-Aug.2010) Job Description: Work in Boiler Maintenance Division Turbine Maintenance Division Plant Auxiliary Maintenance Division Coal Handling Maintenance Division
- Title: Northern Railway Diesel Shed, Summer Training
- Location: Tughlakabad, New Delhi
- Duration: 6 weeks (July-Aug 2011) Job Description: Worked on Air Braking System
 Fuel Injection Pump Super Turbocharger Pit Wheel Governor
- PROJECTS UNDERTAKEN Project: Turbo Jet Engine (Minor & Major) Description: A
 jet engine having a turbine-driven compressor and developing thrust from the
 exhaust of hot gases is a turbojet engine.
- Supervised and motivate team for achieving the target on time.

Languages

English & Hindi

Skills

Business Development, Team Development, Sales and Marketing, New Market searching, Strategic planning, Relationship development, Team Development, Ms-office.

PERSONAL PROFILE

Father's Name : Mr Vinod Maheshwari

Date of Birth : 7th Sep 1989

Sex: MaleMarital Status: MarriedNationality: Indian

Hobbies : Travelling, Driving

Permanent Address: D2/208, Shiv Durga Vihar, Dayal bagh Faridabad 121009

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the information given above is true to the best of my knowledge. $ \\$	
Date:	
Place	(Rajat Maheshwari)